[Music]
hey welcome back you've made it to the
end today is the last day so I'm here
with my campers again better go ahead
and introduce them so we've got Keegan
of course where'd his camp t-shirt by
the way mom and Bowen and McKinley you
guys really good today all right so what
we have to do today so today what we're
making is a game called dragon crossing
so I think dragon crossing is best to
show you
I think that's nothing's work best so
with dragon crossing what we're gonna do
is we're going to try to get our dragon
across the street right it's our dragon
can kind of go up and down and he can
try to get to the street get to the top
ah and if you touch a car you lose but
it just lets you play again now you'll
notice that whenever I did this play
again that everybody just kind of
stopped oh no I'm in trouble
yes oh I got hit so close you'll notice
that everybody just kind of stops
whenever there's a win or a loss happens
and one of the things we're going to be
doing today there was a win one of the
things we're gonna be doing today is
communicating between our different
actors so this like very coordinated hey
everybody stop at the same time all
right now is something that we have to
figure out in code how to do and make
happen
also I mentioned that your theme can be
different from mine so I've got her
dragon crossing a road but really it
just has to be a hero with enemies that
move back and forth and then a victory
at the top so if you wanted to do like
planets or something crazy with
something different color at the top you
could totally I do different things so
let's go and see if we can get started
today so I'm gonna go ahead and make a
new project so I'm going to say create
new project hopefully we're pretty good
on the step every single time I go down
to block coding project but I'm really
sure that they are the same so today I'm
going to risk I'm just gonna go with
blank project and let's go ahead and get
started with drawing some things so the
first thing I'll do is that I don't
actually need my actor my monster so I'm
going to delete him and we've got to
draw a stay
our stage has to have whatever we want
in the middle I'm gonna draw like a road
scene it has to have a victory color at
the top for your victory color it's nice
to go and have a pencil and paper handy
so that you can write down what your
victory color is and then we're also
gonna need to make four different like
enemies so let's go ahead and start off
by drawing some so click on the gear for
the stage click on add backgrounds and
then like we've done so many times we're
going to draw an image and you kind of
have to click on that twice after click
on the paintbrush and then the draw
lemon first thing I like to do is I like
to make my stage fit on my entire screen
so I know I can see everything and I'm
gonna choose to make like a green grass
first it's almost like I'm building a
road so first there's grass and then I'm
gonna put a road on top of it so to make
some green grass I'm gonna pick a color
a nice green here and use my paintbrush
tool and I'm just gonna fill it in all
green after that I'm going to draw my
road and again you can draw something
different if you want you can draw up my
pace you can draw at your own pace
it doesn't really matter but I'm gonna
draw a grey road as a rectangle I'm
gonna pick one of these Gray's and I'm
gonna try to make it such that it takes
up most of the space but leave some
space at the bottom to where my hero can
kind of like start off not just getting
killed right out of the gate right so
there's a nice big rectangle also if you
draw it it's not where you want it
remember that you can always kind of
grab these handles and if it goes really
badly the undo button is useful I next
thing I'm gonna do is I'm gonna draw
some white lines on my room so if I
wanted to draw some white lines draw it
here and then move it and you can draw
it you know like slightly on the road
slightly off the road it doesn't really
matter another trick to keep in mind is
that before you drop it if you want to
be like a pro drawler you can copy/paste
things and copy paste I think it saves a
lot of time today if you get good at
copy paste so I chose to hit ctrl C and
then control V to kind of copy paste it
next thing I'm going to do is I'm going
to draw a bunch of law
on my road I'm gonna have like a
four-lane highway as my goal so what I'm
gonna do is I'm gonna draw a nice yellow
stripe somewhere in the middle and then
after I haven't quite like pasted it to
my background I can do that control-c
control-v and that will help me
you know mass-produce my road and a much
faster system so I cut a few control V's
every now and then get your road made
much quicker so try to get these guys
organized maybe I'll do one more on the
UM you also you'll probably fight with
the tinkerer drawing tool some just try
to get better at drawing it's definitely
useful skill you'll notice that we've
drawn in almost every game we've made
once you get all of the ones made for a
single lane here's an even better trick
you could use this selection tool and
you can highlight an area and even
though it's already like pasted on the
background you can still control C
control V that whole thing and then you
can kind of like make a whole lane at a
time so I'm not worried about what speed
you draw at just kind of get it to where
it looks fun and there's no functional
things happening in this part of the
game anyway so to be honest you could
kind of do whatever you wanted I'm if
you're OCD like me you can see I
accidentally made a little white line
there somehow that was not the goal hold
on I gotta fix that so I'm gonna get rid
of that guy that was whenever I was
copying I kind of made that alright now
let's go ahead and do the functional
part of the screen and that's the
victory color at the top so that's the
only functional part of this game I'm
gonna choose to do a nice I don't know
distinct color maybe I want to go with a
nice pink and I'm just gonna put my
victory color across the whole top I
chose to do it the rectangle but you
could draw it with a pencil whatever you
wanted
now that victory color we are going to
need that so let's go ahead and figure
out what color that is normally we have
two eyedropper it's like select that
color but we've currently got it
selected so I'm just gonna click on the
multicolor wheel here and then hex and
then I'm going to right
down that color I actually used this
color quite a bit so I knew what this
color was it's F F ood five and I
remember it because even though that's a
0 a 0 and a 5 it kind of looks like the
word foods to me I don't know what to
ask
so I actually have that one memorized
which is silly once you've got your
stage drawn you can go back and start
adding some actors you can add as many
actors as you'd like
I'm gonna choose to add 4 and these are
gonna be your your villains right I
think that since it's kind of a car
theme it'd be nice if if I had a couple
cars on here maybe I'll put one of the
yellow cars I think the city life has a
lot of good cars on it here's a neat
little like orange racecar it doesn't
have to be cars though if you don't want
so for example I think I had spaceships
in my previous example so whatever you
would like to do but go through and
pause the video obviously you probably
had to pause it a couple times during
the drawing phase initially I'm just
kind of fighting with the air to make it
smaller and then I'll pick my last
sprite for the top and feel free to do
all the cars but if you wanted to do
something crazy I mean you do do
whatever you want right so here's this
whole sci-fi library maybe I'll have a
t-rex at the top right
don't want to get eaten by a t-rex once
you've got your enemies in there you
need to pick your hero what I'm gonna
pick is my hero
I'm gonna call my game dragon crossing
I'm gonna pick a dragon there's dragons
up in the default area it's one of their
kind of like built-in things and dragons
are crazy cuz dragons when you add it on
you click on this edit dragon it's
what's called a character it's not even
an image it's like a character right and
so you can change whatever you want
about your dragon you can give it a blue
body or you can give it you know
multicolored body
can add crazy things like you know hats
or jewelry I'll give mine a little
necklace here as you do more with tinker
you'll have more and more things get
unlocked and so that's kind of what you
can do with your your character builder
that I'm gonna hit save here so now I've
got a blue dragon now the blue dragon
does come with some code go and hit the
play button and just see what your code
currently does and what your code
currently does which is kind of neat is
when you hold down your mouse button
your dragon flies there that's kind of
cool that's not really that useful for
us but it's something instead of nothing
to start with cool so I consider this
kind of the setup work you probably had
to pause your video a lot with it but
hopefully a lot of these things you
could do without me now what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna save my game so I'm
gonna call mine dragon crossing you can
call yours whatever you want no need to
publish it yeah but this is my
connecting with code day 5 the final day
and I'm just gonna hit save for now I'm
not going to publish it yet I'll publish
it later let's go ahead and glance at
the code that the dragon had to start
with and see if there's any of that that
we would like to keep
so the code in here actually one of my
campers just said that they deleted it
so I'll just delete mine too
we'll just start fresh that way we don't
have to think about what's there alright
so let's go ahead and start in on this
so first off we want to bring over an on
start so our dragon when the game starts
is going to do some stuff and then what
we want this dragon to do is we want him
to do some things forever so if we do
some things forever what he's gonna do
forever is the dragon is going to move
just depending on what direction is so
we need to have some way to switch what
direction we're going and we have to
have some way to move we're also going
to plan ahead a little bit
so you notice how there are times in my
game where everybody stopped right just
like
everybody stopped so what we're gonna do
is every sprite in our game today every
actor is gonna have a variable called
like is game moving and if the game is
moving then they're gonna do their movie
so we're gonna plan ahead we're gonna
make this variable so go ahead and click
on variables and click on create
variable now we want to make a global
variable so it's gonna be for all actors
and maybe we'll just call it like moving
so moving it could be like a 1 people
are moving or a 0 if people stop moving
you can call it a more descriptive name
if you want but I think moving is a fine
fine name and what I'm gonna do is
inside my forever movie instead of just
always having a move I'm gonna like
check that variable first so to check
something you heard me say the word
check that's an if statement so if
statements are over in control and so
we're gonna say if some condition then
run this code and the code we're going
to run is going to be movement let's go
and do that condition first so what we
want to do is we want to check that
variable moving and if it's a 1 then we
are moving and if it's a 0 or not moving
so to check if something as a 1 or a 0
that's an operator's see if you can find
the equals it looks like it's the second
one down in a bullying category here and
you'll notice that it's got that diamond
shape so that means that it's something
that can go in to a condition right and
so we're going to check if moving is
equal to 1 so that's what our two sides
are going to be so go to variables see
if you can find your moving variable
so if moving equals one then we're going
to do some movement again if I go too
fast feel free to pause the video just
trying to help people go at a pace
they're comfortable so we want to move
we could run our game right now but
there's a good chance that nothing will
happen because what's the value of
moving right now we never said it and I
think things probably start off as zero
or even worse they start up as on set so
we've got to do if we want to even see
anything we're going to set moving to be
one at start and then later when we hit
somebody or win I will set it to zero so
let's go ahead and do some setup things
just so we can even see our game working
so the first thing I want to do is I
want to set moving to b1 and so what
this does is this will make my game be
moving by default and later if I want to
make it stop all I'll set it to zero
right while we're doing setup work up
here let's go and do one more thing that
I forgot to do earlier and that is I
want the dragon to only turn left and
right I don't want him to like turn his
body up and so that's a command we'll go
and put it in together then we'll talk
about it it's in motion
it's called set rotation style and the
rotation style that I want to use is
left-right rotation and so what that
does is that will make sure his feet are
always pointed down and you can turn
left and right but there won't ever be a
time where I could speak yo crazy right
now we could run it right now and our
dragon would start moving and our dragon
moved really fast right off the screen I
didn't mean for him to go that fast
campers and the idea what did I forget
to add that'll slow it down some yeah I
forgot to add a weight so I'm moving 10
pixels infinitely fast
is lucky I even saw my dragon so I need
to add a delay a weight a delay is in
the control area it's near the bottom
it's about fourth up from the bottom and
you can drop it in here with your move
10 pixels now the delay that I like to
use I use this and a lot of my games
it's 0.05 kind of a crazy number but
it's one twentieth of a second it makes
our game move at about 20 frames per
second and I find that that's a good a
good number to kind of make things work
about right so if I run it now it's
better it's still not great what happens
is my my dragon kind of slowly glides
off the screen while that's interesting
but isn't really what I was after
so I want to do two things one is when I
get to the edge I want to bounce back so
I'm gonna add that it's in motion
and it's if on edge bounce you can put
it wherever you want in your code I'm
gonna put it right after the movement
and then also I don't like how my dragon
was kind of like just gliding right this
is a character it's got more advanced
things of that so I want my dragon to
like look like it's walking or running
or something like that and so let's go
into looks now there's two ways you can
do this I'm going to show you the the
way that I like to do it and I like to
say switch to costume run now there's a
couple different ways to do that I think
the the code that came in actually used
an animation and so they had like an
animate run
I actually prefer this one the switch to
costume run because it will stop
instantly if you want to someday you can
play with both but this is the one that
I want so now it should do things better
it should have my dragon
animating kind of like a switching to
costume run now you notice that Ron is a
little different from costumes we've
using the past run is actually a list of
costumes so by calling switch to costume
run it actually does animate through
different things it doesn't just switch
to one costume but that's kind of neat
you can also speed your dragon up a
little bit maybe like 15 or 20 would
make for a more interesting dragon
speeding I think 15 I don't know it just
kind of feels like it's running better
cool so my game is making good progress
I've got my hero running back and forth
and so what I want to do is I want to
make my hero be able to change
directions right so if I hit like up
arrow I want the dragon to go up if I
hit right right now it would go right or
down or left cool so let's go ahead and
see if we can add some things to let our
hero change direction so what I'm
looking for is events
and I'm going to start grabbing these
different arrow key presses so inside of
minutes I grab the third one down and I
said win up arrow pressed so when an up
arrow is pressed I want my dragon to
point up so that's in motion and it's
point in direction I always got to find
it right here we go point in direction
and I want it to be up so I kind of
click on the zero up here and hopefully
it pops to zero and that's actually
enough I couldn't test my game now so if
I run it now my dragon started by
running to the right and if I hit the up
arrow then it switches to to running up
which is good so go ahead and pause the
video for a minute and see if you can
get in all four directions I'm going to
choose not to show you mine
I'm just going to let you do it but
pause the video and see if you can get
in up down left and right
alright so I got the rest of mine added
in so up left right down you can look at
the numbers here but even better is you
know you you just click on it and then
you you see the value right there and
make sure that your dragon moves around
or whatever your hero is so when I hit
left goes left up goes up right goes
right down goes down and if you hit a
wall
you should bounce off of it now my
campers in here the first thing they did
is they discovered that if you hold down
a button you can kind of sort of go into
the wall a little bit that's not really
the goal but that's what that's what my
campers discovered alright so let's go
ahead and save it real quick so go and
click on save so we've done a lot of
coding we don't want to lose that and
let's actually start working on our
first of our enemies so you can start
with any one you want
I think I'm gonna start with the the
convertible here and one thing that
happens a lot in coding is if you click
on the convertible right now you can see
they has no code at all we could totally
write their code from scratch that would
be no problem but one thing that you do
a lot in coding is go back to your hero
we can go back to the dragon if you
think about this thread right here just
this thread not not all the winds if you
think about just this thread this is
actually pretty similar to what the what
the enemies are gonna do because they're
gonna have to forever if they're moving
move pixels and go back and forth so
what we're gonna do is we're gonna save
ourselves some time so I'm gonna click
on this little handle on the left of one
start and I'm going to take this block
of code and I'm gonna drop it onto one
of these other sprites so I'm gonna drop
it onto my blue convertible now when
that when you let go like when you drop
it there it stays in the dragon so it's
not like you you you cut it out but if
you go to the convertible now I you can
see that you've got a lot of code to
start with which is which is cool so
there are some things that we don't want
right there are some things that we're
going to change but this same
this time right and when you when you do
a lot of software development people
people love to save time right so let's
think about what's different at this
well the first thing that's different is
each car is not responsible for this
variable moving so I actually don't
really it doesn't do anything bad but I
don't really need this command for each
car so what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
click on the right handle and the right
handle selects just that one and I'm
just gonna pop that one out now you
could set it over here that'd be fine
but I just don't need it at all so I'm
just gonna drag it over the trashcan
likewise you'll notice that my car here
has this switch to costume run that was
for the dragon right a car doesn't even
have a run so I want to pop that out as
well and again you could set it over
here if you wanted but I don't really
need it so I'm just gonna throw it in
the trash and the neat thing is is that
just by copying that code and going here
you can see that my car is moving now
this car had some unexpected behavior
this car is moving the wrong direction
well that's something I I was not
expecting that
so since my car is moving the wrong
direction what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna
go into their image and point them to go
that way right there's a couple
different ways you could do it but my
car my convertible is going the wrong
direction I think I know how to do this
so if you have a vehicle that's going
the wrong direction click on this little
like dotted square drag it over your
whole car trying to make your car as
centered as possible inside of it and
then there's a button down here I
believe which is supposed to flip the
direction of the car I don't click click
on it again so you can flip your car
such that it's pointing to the right
that was that was a very unexpected
feature whenever I practice this game it
didn't come up so I flipped it to the
right alright I think it's finally
behaving properly
so if I hit play my car is going the
correct direction again super alright so
a little a little stumble there so let's
go write some more code in him so he
wants to go back and forth that's all
true but the convertible also has a job
and his job is to check to see if he's
touching the dragon now the dragon
couldn't check to see if he's touching
like the blue car and the yellow car and
the orange car do you check them all
there it's actually easier for the cars
because they don't have to check for one
thing they just have to check for the
dragon so what I want to do is I want to
check for the dragon to check for
something as an if-statement so I go
into control and I find an if statement
and you can put this if statement in a
couple different places I'm going to
choose to put it right after the
movement right so I move and then I'm
gonna check hey am i hitting the dragon
right now that if check right here this
is a sensing type of thing so let's go
into sensing and what we want to do is
we want to this is always kind of funny
we want to drag over if touching mouse
pointer wait why did I put in mouse
pointer and it's because mouse pointer
is an argument to this function and you
can change it and you can find your hero
so for me my hero is a dragon so I'm
gonna say if touching dragon then so now
this this is the next question my car's
right here he's not he's not like the
one who's in charge of this game but he
knows he's the one who has the smarts I
just touched the dragon and so he needs
to somehow tell everybody else everybody
stop moving and the way you do that is
you broadcast and events so this is
something new right so this is a brand
new skill or learning go up to events
and events or things that happen like an
event is the game starts or an actor
Clint but you can also make your own
events so scroll down a little bit until
I could get into this events area and
find the one that says broadcast
asked and then has a little box next to
it and drag it and put it inside here
and so what he's gonna do is he's gonna
broadcast which means tell everybody
else that something happened and he's
gonna broadcast a new event called hit
and so he's gonna say hit and so just
everybody everybody with ears to hear I
can hear him say it right now maybe he's
the one that yells hit but I'm gonna put
this coat on everybody else right so
I'll tell off let's go ahead and do that
really quick just cuz it'll be fun take
this code and give it to the yellow car
and then take this code and also give it
to the orange car and take this code and
give it to the t-rex so now if you hit
play it's gonna be like crazy which will
be kind of fun if you hit play now
everybody moves they're all going the
exact same speed right now your dragon
is the only one that has the ability to
steer and what we're gonna do is
whenever you hit somebody they're gonna
broadcast this message hit so they're
all broadcasting hit right now so every
time I hit one of these guys they're
screaming hit like if only I could hear
them scream but nobody's like doing
anything right so it's like somebody
else fire but nobody boost so let's go
ahead and do the other side of that
let's listen for somebody to say hit so
the person that's gonna listen for this
hit is actually the dragon so the dragon
is gonna listen so I'm just going to
kind of move this code out of the way a
little bit it's gonna listen and say
when I receive so when the dragon
receives hit he knows hey I've been hit
and the dragons job is to tell everybody
to stop moving right that's the nice
thing about this variable so everybody's
got this variable moving that they're
listening for so I want to tell
everybody to stop moving for a second
so I go to variables I go to set and if
I set moving to zero then everybody's
gonna stop let's just check them
sure that that works so when I hit
somebody they yell hit and then when the
dragon hears them y'all hit he says
everybody stop so I run it now I'm just
gonna run right into somebody I'm and as
soon as I hit them everybody stops now
interestingly the game is still running
it's just that nobody is moving because
moving has been set to zero so it's a
really neat way to communicate so we've
learned two ways to communicate one is
to broadcast an event hit and then
another is with global variables right
so he tells everybody now whenever he
does get hit so whatever the dragon gets
hit he wants to tell everybody to freeze
um he wants to say some things and then
he's gonna let the game carry on so if
he wants to say something that's in
looks and find the big scary save up
block the one that has the for two
seconds on it and the dragon is gonna
say ouch and then he's gonna say play
again
why should mark alright and you can
check that if you want to check it just
by running into somebody so now
everybody will stop and it'll say ouch
play again it says that for two seconds
if you want to make it happen for three
seconds you can and then what I want to
do is I want to reset the game before I
restart playing again right so to reset
the game what I want to do is I want to
move my dragon back to a good starting
spot now the best way to find a good
starting spot is just to kind of move
your mouse to that spot and personally I
like to just write the number down
really quick mine is negative five sixty
negative 279 I find that writing it down
just makes life easier than trying to
memorize it and so now I'm gonna go to
motion I'm going to say go to X Y and
I'm going to type in that number I think
I'm gonna type in 280 just because I
always like nice round number
the 270 died and you can keep testing
things in small chunks but now it should
say ouch play again and then it should
move you back to the start I think that
looks pretty good actually I might
prefer mine just a little lower maybe
I'll do negative to 300 being very picky
here sometimes whenever you're the game
designer you're picky though so he says
I'll play again so it resets the dragon
to that spot I also want to make sure
because I might have been going up when
I died I want to make sure that I'm
pointing to the right because when I
reset the game I always want to start to
the right because I've kind of got that
safe zone at the bottom so I want to
find point in direction here's the point
in direction I don't want to make sure
it says 90 degrees which is the default
so now even if I'm going up at the
moment I die I'm going to be going to
the right here and then what I'm gonna
choose to do this is optional I'm gonna
choose to wait for one more second just
so the person can kind of like get their
bearings again waiting for a second was
in control and delay is like forth on
the bottom we use that one all the time
and then I'm gonna restart the game so
to restart the game I just got to go
back into variables I've got to find set
moving and to restart the game I'm gonna
set it to 1 and everybody is gonna hear
that because their code if you go look
at it it says if moving then they're
gonna like come back to life right so
let's go ahead and try our game so now I
should be able to walk around or no
they're all coming for me and if I hit
somebody it says ouch play again and
then it puts me back to the bottom it
waits for a second just to let the
player kind of get their bearings and
then it plays again hi I'm in trouble
I'll play again and then it takes you to
the bottom
so to be honest our game is fully ready
except for we can't win right so if you
get to the top you can't win another
thing that I'd like to change is I'd
like to make my cars be different speeds
right I think I'm gonna implement win
first so I'm gonna win first and then
I'm gonna create a way for my cars to
kind of like be at variable speeds it
kind of makes for like an interesting
pattern if they all go at different
speeds or as like right now it's pretty
easy to win right I just kind of go
straight up at the top all right so
let's go ahead and and check for a win
so to check for a win my dragon has to
check if they're touching that color at
the top so a check is an in-state lift
so go into an if statement and we have
to think about where do we want this if
statement and where I want this if
statement is I want it right after where
the dragon moves so the dragon moves and
then I want to check if I'm if I've won
the game right I always like to put it
right after a move because that's the
moment where I can know if it happens
and the thing I want to check for is I
want to check check if I'm touching a
color and so I'm going to go ahead and
go to sensing and this time we want
touching color by the way this is a good
time to reflect on things so sometimes
you're touching another actor and in
that case you say touching mouse pointer
the new changes that actor and other
times you want touching color and so you
use this touching color and with that
you have to go figure out what that
color was in your stage now I planned
ahead and I wrote down my color long ago
and my color is my favorite color which
is foods but I'm kinda remember it's not
OHS it's actually zeros and a 5 right so
my color is that
I've written it down earlier again if
you're working in this box make sure you
get good at using the left and right
arrow keys so click in there once with
your mouse and then never click again
with your mouse and then use the left
and right arrow keys and delete to kind
of like work in that text box so you'll
know that it works when this color
matches that color
so I think that I've got that set now
inside of here we want something to
happen there's a bunch of ways you could
implement this you could put code like
this this code right here right in there
that would be fine you could make a
function that would be fine but today
we're learning about broadcasting events
and listening for events so we're gonna
do something that's a little silly but
but it's good for practice we're gonna
make an event that we broadcast called
win and then we are gonna listen for it
and that is a little unnecessary you
could just call a function or something
like that but I want to practice with
events today so let's go and practice
our last event for today so click on
events and whenever I'm touching that
color I've got a broadcast the event win
now anybody could listen for win that
would be fine but instead what I'm gonna
do is I'm gonna listen for my own events
right so i broadcast win and then i'm
gonna listen for it over here and the
reason I wanted to do it this way is
because win is actually pretty similar
to hit so to save time cuz I like the
save time I'm gonna make a copy of this
event so I collect it with the left
handle I hit control C and I hit control
V and now I'm gonna change it so this
was my hit up here and this is my win
down here so when I receive win
everybody stops moving just like they
did before except for I'm gonna say you
win you win I always think it's
interesting when you make games how
similar the code is to wedding and lose
because you either win or you lose but
either way the game is over it's just a
matter of what you say to your player
and in this case we're gonna stop
everybody moving say you win if you'd
like you can also ask them to play again
so you win play again and then you're
gonna go back to the start
you're gonna point in the correct
direction you're gonna wait to let them
get their bearings and then you're gonna
start it up so I think we just finished
this game so it's time to try it out
Oh actually there's one more thing I
want to do I want my cars to go at all
different speeds so I'm gonna have like
one car go at twenty another car go at
like thirty and you can decide what good
speeds are but I like for my cars to
kind of go at all different speeds so I
just clicked on each car so my yellow
car I made him go twenty my orange car
he's my slow boo he's gonna go it how
many go super slow at ten my convertible
is at thirty and then my t-rex my top
one I for my top one would be the
fastest right that he's kind of like the
hardest challenge all right time to try
it I might have made it too hard right
so they're all at different speeds which
makes your game more interesting because
now their patterns are gonna like get
different see they don't all go together
right so I'm gonna try to get try to get
there I think here's a good Avenue to
get to the top yeah you win play again
cool so it looks like mine is working Oh
so the idea of these games is that you
get an opportunity to code and make a
game but it's also a fun way to play
your own game and make sure you have
like you know brothers and sisters go
try your game and things like that
and this one I think is is fully running
hey I'm gonna give my campers just a
minute to finish their game but I'm
gonna go ahead and hit save and publish
online publish to community save and
publish I that way other people can see
my game
people can see what I've been doing I'm
gonna come around and show my other
campers and their games hey but I'm
gonna bitchin
the extra project today if you want the
extra project is a separate video I'm
just going to kind of mention what it is
it's to try to practice with functions
and it's to try to make a US flag so I'm
just showing this there's a whole nother
video for it it's an extra thing that
you can do that uses functions so that
is another video that you could watch if
you wanted all right so I'm gonna go
around and see how my campers did on
this alright Keegan are you ready to go
all right so Keegan I mean he has he's
done something interesting he has
multiple clever Keegan he has multiple
villains in each row so there could be
just one but his game is quite difficult
which is great he get one thing you can
do to make your game more fun is make
your goblin move faster so see how you
can change your code to do that alright
Bo did you make a game today oh oh it
just one is game all right boom let's
take a look to see what you've got
Bowens favorite color is green so I kind
of thought he'd stick with a green
dragon and Bowens got some cars in here
oh he's got a motorcycle it's very
javelin and so though I saw this you
could lose games alright going you're on
camera see if you can win a game are you
ready
alright so he's thinking about it he's
going for it
watch out for the motorcycle boy which
one's the fastest yeah that top is super
good you have one bill but today the
boat alright McKinley
let's look at your game today oh you've
got a different you didn't use the road
theme you used a different backdrop that
was very clever oh you've got lava cools
you've got different lava fields you got
destroyed play again on I like your text
box the sea and you chose to go with
temple red dragon which is fun red and
orange top quite hard your top row is
quite hard alright so that's it that's
it for Curtin Camp you guys finish the
last assignment did you guys have fun at
Cody camp
alright now go ahead and say goodbye to
everybody we really appreciate you
joining us if you'd like to get a
t-shirt they're still on sale for a
couple more days
I think t-shirts help remind you of
coding and things like that but we
really loved having you and we'll see
you some other time
[Music]